

Kwangmin Kim

Data Scientist/ Data Analyst

Email: kmink3225@gmail.com Website: kmink3225.netlify.app

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kwangmin-kim-a5241b200/

ABOUT ME

Over 7 years of experience in data modeling, data pre-processing, data analytics, and statistical/ML modeling. As a product owner, I communicated with other departments and directly managed and completed projects. I was selected for the Platform Planning TF Team under the Strategic Planning Office and gained a high understanding of the platform. I also collaborated with the in-house patent center to invent technologies helpful for corporate assetization.

I am interested in gaining a mathematical understanding of algorithms and modeling. I communicate with the collaborating departments using detailed objective facts obtained through data analysis. I aim to work in a planned, systematic way.

SKILLS

Data Scinece	Database	etc
• R, Python	SQlite	• Ubuntu, Powershell, Git/Github, Conda
• SAS	• Oracle-SQL	• Quarto, R markdown, Jupyter,

EXPERIENCE

2020.12 - Present

Seegene, Diagnosis IT General Research Institute, Data Science Team

- Data Scientist / Data Analyst
- Algorithm DHF documentation and FDA verification & validation reporting.
- Diagnosis algorithms management and development.
- Device QC (Quality Control) algorithms management and development.
- Data analytic and statistical analysis.
- IP (Intellectual Property) planning and filed 9 patent inventions.

2018.12 - 2020.04

Columbia University Irving Medical Center, Taub Institute for Research on Alzheimer's Disease and the Aging Brain Research Statistician

- Clinical data analytics pipeline construction.
- Clinical data analytics: statistics, machine learning(ML), data mining, pathway analysis.
- ML and statistics consulting to medical doctors, epidemiologists, and neurologists.

EDUCATION

2017.08 - 2019.05 2015.08 - 2017.05 2006.03 - 2012.02

- Columbia University in the City of New York, Biostatistics(MS), Department Head Award
- Baruch College, The City University of New York, Mathematics(BA)
- Kangwon National University, Biochemistry(BS), Summa Cum Laude, Full Scholarship

PROJECTS		AWARDS
2022.07 - present	 Algorithm DHF & FDA Verification & Validation Documentation Seegene, Diagnosis IT General Research Institute Diagnosis algorithm DHF planning and documentation. FDA verification & validation report documentation. Designed algorithm testing and constructed statistical analysis pipelines for algorithm verification as the product manager. Dynamic documentation using Quarto, R, and python. 	
2021.12 - 2022.07	 Platform Planning TF Seegene, Strategy Planning Office & In-house Patent Center Platform strategy planning and intellectual property planning. 5/16 inventions have been filed(the remaining 11 are ongoing). Database system, statistics, and ML knowledge consultation for executives, planners, and attorneys. 	Invention Compensation
2021.01 - 2021.09	 Data-Driven Diagnosis Algorithm Development Seegene, Strategy Planning Office & In-house Patent Center Planned and developed a data-driven signal processing algorithm. Reflected optical characteristics of diagnosis device. Reflected the unique technology of SG reagents. 	R&D Division Excellence Award Invention Compensation
2019.05 - 2020.04	 Diagnosis Device Quality Control (QC) Platform Construction Seegene, Diagnosis IT General Research Institute led all processes throughout the project as the product owner. Developed noise measurement algorithms. Collaborated with other departements to automate the two-stage QC process, visualize it, and reduce turnaround time by 11x. Classified device failures, human errors, and production line errors. 	
2018.12 - 2019.05	 Long Life Family Study (LLFS) Project Columbia University Irving Medical Center, Taub Institute Used statistics and ML to identify metabolic profiles significantly associated with dementia Analytics pipeline consturction: missing value analysis, statistical analysis, ML classification, and pathway analysis Using data mining, a strong confounder was discovered that had not been found by the research institute for 8 months 	Department Head Award \$1,000 Stipend Job Offer
	 Analytic Project on Alzheimer's Disease and the Aging Brain Columbia University in the City of New York, Biostatistics Selected as one of the top 3 out of about 100 graduate students in the annual research competition for master's graduate students Comparative study of optimal ML methods for Alzheimer's Disease and the Aging Brain and metabolomics 	\$1,000 Stipend
2015.01 - 2015.06	 Using Tea Leaves, Heavy Metal Removal Algorithm Development The City University of New York, Mathematics Developed a mechanistic model that reflects the adsorption process of heavy metals into tea leaves using differential equation and non-linear least square algorithm 	